<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<technical-decisions xmlns:h="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
                     xmlns="https://niap-ccevs.org/cc/v1">
    <bunch>
        <applies-to max-inclusive="4.0" name="Mobile Device Management"/>

        <decision id='0461'>
            <notes>Security Audit for Distributed TOEs</notes>

            <change xpath=".//subsection[@id='dis']" mode="replace">
                <subsection id="dis" title="Security Audit for Distributed TOEs">
                    <h:br/>
                    For distributed<abbr linkend="TOE"/>s the handling of audit information might be more complicated
                    than for<abbr linkend="TOE"/>s consisting only of one component. There are a few basic requirements
                    to be fulfilled:
                    <h:br/>
                    <h:br/>
                    <h:ul>
                        <h:li>Every component must be able to generate audit information.</h:li>
                        <h:li>Every component must be able to buffer audit information and forward it to another
                            <abbr linkend="TOE"/>
                            component or an external audit server. Optionally, each component may store audit
                            information locally.
                        </h:li>
                        <h:li>For the overall
                            <abbr linkend="TOE"/>
                            it must be possible to send out audit information to an external audit server.
                        </h:li>
                    </h:ul>
                    <h:br/>
                    In general, every component must be able to generate its own audit information. It would be possible
                    that every component also stores its own audit information locally as well as every component could
                    be able to send out audit data to an external audit server. It would also be sufficient that every
                    component would be able to generate its own audit data and buffer it locally before the information
                    is sent out to one or more other
                    <abbr linkend="TOE"/>
                    components for local storage and/or transmission to an external audit server. For the transfer of
                    audit records between
                    <abbr linkend="TOE"/>
                    components the secure connection via FTP_ITC.1 or<linkref linkend="FPT_ITT.1(1)"/>/
                    <linkref linkend="FPT_ITT.1(2)"/>
                    must be used.
                    <h:br/>
                    <h:br/>

                    Such a solution would still be suitable to fulfil the requirement that all audit-related<abbr
                        linkend="SFR"/>s have to be fulfilled by all
                    <abbr linkend="TOE"/>
                    components, although formally not every component would support local storage or transfer to an
                    external audit server itself.
                    <h:br/>
                    <h:br/>

                    Regarding the establishment of inter-
                    <abbr linkend="TOE"/>
                    communication, error conditions as well as successful connection/teardown events should be captured
                    by both ends of the connection.
                    <h:br/>
                    <h:br/>

                    All
                    <abbr linkend="TOE"/>
                    components shall be able to generate its own audit data according to FAU_GEN.1 for all<abbr
                        linkend="SFR"/>s that it implements. For distributed<abbr linkend="TOE"/>s, a mapping shall be
                    provided to show which auditable events according to FAU_GEN.1 are covered by which components (also
                    giving a justification that the records generated by each component cover all the<abbr
                        linkend="SFR"/>s that it implements). The overall
                    <abbr linkend="TOE"/>
                    has to provide audit information about all events defined for FAU_GEN.1. As a result, at least one
                    <abbr linkend="TOE"/>
                    component has to be assigned to every auditable event defined for FAU_GEN.1. The part of the mapping
                    related to
                    <ctr-ref ref-id="audit"/>
                    shall be consistent with the mapping of<abbr linkend="SFR"/>s to
                    <abbr linkend="TOE"/>
                    components for ASE_TSS.1 in the sense that all components defined as generating audit information
                    for a particular SFR should also contribute to that SFR in the mapping for ASE_TSS.1. This applies
                    not only to audit events defined for mandatory<abbr linkend="SFR"/>s but also to all audit events
                    for optional, selection-based, and objective<abbr linkend="SFR"/>s as defined in<appref
                        linkend="optional"/>,<appref linkend="sel-based"/>, and<appref linkend="objective"/>.
                    <h:br/>
                    <h:br/>

                    If one or more of the optional audit components
                    <linkref linkend="FAU_STG_EXT.1"/>
                    or
                    <linkref linkend="FAU_STG_EXT.2"/>
                    are selected in the
                    <abbr linkend="ST"/>
                    derived from this<abbr linkend="PP"/>, then the
                    <abbr linkend="SFR"/>
                    mapping for ASE_TSS.1 must include a specific identification of the
                    <abbr linkend="TOE"/>
                    components to which they apply.
                </subsection>
            </change>

        </decision>
    </bunch>
</technical-decisions>
