<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<technical-decisions xmlns:h="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
                     xmlns="https://niap-ccevs.org/cc/v1">
    <bunch>
        <applies-to max-inclusive="4.0" name="Mobile Device Management"/>

        <decision id='0438'>
            <notes>TST and TUD on the MDM Agent</notes>
            <change xpath=".//chapter[@id='idt']/section[2]/htm:table/htm:tr[46]" mode="replace">
                <h:tr>
                    <h:td>
                        <linkref linkend="FPT_TST_EXT.1"/>
                    </h:td>
                    <h:td>Functionality Testing</h:td>
                    <h:td>All (except for Agent components)</h:td>
                </h:tr>
            </change>
            <change xpath=".//f-element[@id='fpt_tst_ext.1.2']" mode="replace">
                <f-element id="fpt_tst_ext.1.2">
                    <title>The TSF shall
                        <selectables>
                            <selectable>invoke platform-provided functionality</selectable>
                            <selectable>implement functionality</selectable>
                        </selectables>
                        to provide the capability to verify the integrity of stored
                        <abbr linkend="TSF"/>
                        executable code when it is loaded for execution through the use of the
                        <selectables>
                            <selectable>TSF</selectable>
                            <selectable>
                                <abbr linkend="TOE"/>
                                platform
                            </selectable>
                        </selectables>
                        -provided cryptographic services.
                    </title>
                    <note role="application">While the
                        <abbr linkend="TOE"/>
                        is typically a software package running in the IT Environment, it is still capable of performing
                        the self-test activities required above. It should be understood, however, that there is a
                        significant dependency on the host environment in assessing the assurance provided by the tests
                        mentioned above (meaning that if the host environment is compromised, the self-tests will not be
                        meaningful).
                        <h:br/>
                        <h:br/>
                        For distributed<abbr linkend="TOE"/>s all
                        <abbr linkend="TOE"/>
                        components (except the Agent components) have to perform self-tests. This does not necessarily
                        mean that each
                        <abbr linkend="TOE"/>
                        component has to carry out the same self-tests: the
                        <abbr linkend="ST"/>
                        describes the applicability of the selection (i.e. when self-tests are run) and the final
                        assignment (i.e. which self-tests are carried out) to each
                        <abbr linkend="TOE"/>
                        component.
                    </note>
                    <aactivity>
                        <TSS>If "invoke platform-provided functionality" is selected, the evaluator shall examine the
                            <abbr linkend="TSS"/>
                            to verify that it describes (for each supported platform) how this functionality is invoked
                            (it should be noted that this may be through a mechanism that is not implemented by the
                            <abbr linkend="MDM"/>
                            Server; nonetheless, that mechanism will be identified in the
                            <abbr linkend="TSS"/>
                            as part of this evaluation activity).
                            <h:br/>
                            <h:br/>
                            If "implement functionality" is selected, the evaluator shall examine the
                            <abbr linkend="TSS"/>
                            to ensure that it details the self-tests that are run by the
                            <abbr linkend="TSF"/>
                            on start-up; this description should include an outline of what the tests are actually doing
                            (e.g., rather than saying "memory is tested", a description similar to "memory is tested by
                            writing a value to each memory location and reading it back to ensure it is identical to
                            what was written" shall be used). The evaluator shall ensure that the
                            <abbr linkend="TSS"/>
                            makes an argument that the tests are sufficient to demonstrate that the
                            <abbr linkend="TSF"/>
                            is operating correctly.
                            <h:br/>
                            <h:br/>
                            The evaluator shall examine the
                            <abbr linkend="TSS"/>
                            to ensure that it describes how to verify the integrity of stored
                            <abbr linkend="TSF"/>
                            executable code when it is loaded for execution. The evaluator shall ensure that the
                            <abbr linkend="TSS"/>
                            makes an argument that the tests are sufficient to demonstrate that the integrity of stored
                            <abbr linkend="TSF"/>
                            executable code has not been compromised. The evaluator also ensures that the
                            <abbr linkend="TSS"/>
                            (or the operational guidance) describes the actions that take place for successful (e.g.
                            hash verified) and unsuccessful e.g., hash not verified) cases.
                            <h:br/>
                            <h:br/>
                        </TSS>
                        <Tests>The evaluator shall perform the following tests:
                            <testlist>
                                <test>The evaluator performs the integrity check on a known good
                                    <abbr linkend="TSF"/>
                                    executable and verifies that the check is successful.
                                </test>
                                <test>The evaluator modifies the
                                    <abbr linkend="TSF"/>
                                    executable, performs the integrity check on the modified
                                    <abbr linkend="TSF"/>
                                    executable and verifies that the check fails.
                                </test>
                            </testlist>
                        </Tests>
                    </aactivity>
                </f-element>
            </change>

            <change xpath=".//f-element[@id='fpt_tud_ext.1.1']" mode="replace">
                <f-element id="fpt_tud_ext.1.1">
                    <title>The
                        <abbr linkend="TSF"/>
                        shall provide Authorized Administrators the ability to query the current version of the
                        software.
                    </title>
                    <note role="application">
                        For a distributed TOE, the method of determining the installed versions on each component of the
                        <abbr linkend="TOE"/>
                        is described in the operational guidance. In the requirement, "software" refers to the component
                        of the distributed TOE to which the requirement is being applied.
                    </note>
                    <aactivity>
                        <Guidance>The evaluator shall ensure that the administrator guidance includes instructions for
                            determining the current version of the<abbr linkend="TOE"/>.
                            <h:br/>
                            <h:br/>
                        </Guidance>
                        <Tests>The evaluator shall query the
                            <abbr linkend="TSF"/>
                            for the current version of the software according to the AGD guidance and shall verify that
                            the current version matches that of the documented and installed version.
                        </Tests>
                    </aactivity>
                </f-element>
            </change>

        </decision>
    </bunch>
</technical-decisions>
